Neurologically, the vertebral plexuses essentially consist of 4-5 parts.
You have what's called the medullary system, deep,
the internal spinal veins system between the dura mater and the dural sinus,
and then the external vertebral venous plexus.
We also have the diploic systems and emissaries that are even more specific at the level of the
skull.
You have a medullary plexus, and you also have a whole internal plexus here.
And that's very interesting; it's a whole network, especially the pterygoid sinus,
here, which is a phase of congestion.
You need to learn to release this system.
It's a valve; it's as if there were a congestion.
So when you have chronic cervical pain or someone who comes in with acute torticollis, it's
often due to venous compressions.
You look at a cross-section of a nerve, the perineurium, the endoneurium, the epineurium.
Inside that cross-section of a nerve, you find
small vessels that can congest and compress the system
neuronal and neurological. So we have a role where we can decongest that, a
discopathy.
In fact, these are stases; they release cytokines, they release acidity that starts
to destroy the system, rebalancing the pressures. This is also the dural sinus,
it's continuous as well as the vertebral plexus. The sacrum can relieve your pains.
as all this venous blood goes into what's called the superior sagittal sinus
sagittal
inferior and straight and transverse sinus as
if it goes there; that's why
it's also related to something very interesting
At the level of my fourth ventricle, it's the Magendie hole.
And what is it?
It's the opening; it's almost a pulsation we find with the
CSF system.
By releasing Ignon, by releasing from the periphery to the depth
this whole system,
you will reopen all vascular fields and drain the whole vascular system as well.
Entrance gate, carotid, vertebral artery, exit gate.
all this drainage of the sinuses via the vertebral plexus.
It's therefore a free sacrum.
The pelvic veins and those of the lower limbs form a functional unit.
This means that an imbalance in my lower limbs,
feet, knees, pelvis here, affects the urogenital system.
I'll give an example.
Every time I walk, I perform drainage with the arch of the foot.
I have a kind of diaphragm underneath called the scaphoid-cuboid joint.
The first thing we do to check in pelvic issues in women,
is that we check the foot.
We will release the foot, as we can, so that we regain this
return force.
Otherwise, it creates a stasis.
There are women who come in with lower limb pain.
In fact, if it's internal in the nerve, we should consider looking at
the system.
the system if it's not urogenital.
This is also, as we discussed, certain collateral pathways are merely the reappearance
of a circulatory state observed in the fetus which regresses under physiological conditions.
In a retroverted uterus, you often have congestions occurring; be careful,
there is in fact a valve insufficiency causing circulation in both directions, remember, I explained
that this venous circulation could change.
It took other directions. I start this way, but then I have a congestion; I go back
this way.
And I can stagnate, I can create local congestion areas, prostate,
etc.
These are congestions they will create, and I can take another path.
Abdominal pressure influences the path of venous blood, just as I said.
So, when abdominal pressure increases, what happens?
It will head towards what? Towards the vertebral plexuses.
So, vertebral congestion, low back pain, you have low back pain of digestive origin.
Often, people come to you, but they haven't lifted anything; they're just stuck.
In fact, we need to restore the pressures to relieve the liver, to give back dynamic balance
here.
Venous circulation disorders would be the cause of deep dyspareunia,
persistent.
the hours following intercourse, dysmenorrhea, constipation,
tenesmus, general affliction,
asthenia, spastic tendencies, and emotional irritability.
Look at everything this can generate.
The big key is the diaphragmatic pump, at
once vascular, once arterial
and at the same time...
Fatigue?
The development of the vascular system results in blood pressure developing.
I have the capillary system.
At some point, there is this pressure.
And in fact, this will create exudates.
It's the intercellular network.
And this network will create new pathways,
essentially pathways that are purely longitudinal at first
here,
with a very important network.
important we call the Pecquet cistern or the chyle cistern, with especially
a large
absorption at the level of the left subclavian. The psoas, along with the perineal fascia,
drain up to 1.5 liters of lymph per day through these movements. The
psoas actually corresponds to an organ that is quite thick and can store toxins. That's why I
can lock myself
because of my life.
The psoas represents a toxic overload that does not release from my peritoneum
and ends up in my venous system and then later back into my lymphatic system.
And I cannot drain.
And you have a small muscle that resembles that in the neck.
The psoas, the angular part of the scapula.
It's really like... It's thick like this.
If you say it, it inserts in the same way and settles down like this.
It's a muscle thick like this.
It's also a muscle that takes on toxicity.
Don't forget that...
I believe there are seven diaphragms: the feet, the knees, the small
pelvis, thoracic here,
Simpson, cerebellar tonsil, and all the balance with the base of the skull, and then my parietals here.
It's important, why? Because here, what do I have above? I have one of the most important
drainage spaces for the CSF system, absorption. Your parietals need to breathe,
they are solar panels; they need to take in light.
The radius are solar bones.
Then, we will reintegrate all this with the brain, with the different connections
we saw.
We will finally reintegrate this with the vitelline system, the umbilical system, the apical shock, to
also release the brain.